SENIOR BUSINESS SYSTEMS ANALYST

Career Overview

Highly Motivated and Performance driven professional with 10 years of Business Analysis experience working on wide range of projects including UI, Claims, Security, Mobile Apps and Product Related. Solid understanding of Agile and Waterfall methodologies. Excellent Analytical, Communication, Interpersonal and Presentation skills. Accomplished track record of successfully managing multiple projects simultaneously

Certifications

IIBA Certified Business Analysis Professional

Skills

MS Office (Word, Excel, Power point)

MS Visio

XML

SQL

Quality Center/ALM

Accomplishments

- Completed business requirements analysis including the evaluation of systems specifications and created Story cards ahead of deadline so there is enough buffer pool of cards for the developers and the project time lines are on track.
- Identified, recommended and prioritized the gaps existing in the new system Vs the Legacy system so they can be used as the High level requirements for the Second phase of the project.
- Served as leader on huge projects mentoring the fellow RAs to produce high quality work products.
- Collaborated with Project Manager in organizing the work into multiple iterations before the projects official execution.
- Acted as the first point of contact on all projects for Business contacts, Developers, Testers and Project Managers on all requirements related tasks from Requirements gathering and Analysis to Development and Testing effort completion

Work Experience

Senior Business Systems Analyst Dec 2006 to Current

Transamerica Life Insurance Company il Saint Petersburg, FL

- Acted as a Liaison between Business and IT in identifying, clarifying and communicating requirements
- Worked closely with Business in developing business case
- Presented over all scope and the business analysis approach to the stakeholders.
- Worked closely in Lead Analyst Capacity with Project Manager, Business Lead, Technical Lead, QA Lead and created the product based planning deliverables which identified the products the project needs to deliver, Product breakdown structure and Product flow diagram.
- Helped the Project manager and QA Lead with creating the project acceptance criteria document
- Created Context Diagrams, Use Cases, Process Flows to Identify and communicate requirements
- Worked closely with Project manager in Iteration management activities. Served as an iteration manager for some projects
- Worked in both Agile and Water fall methodologies
- · Working on agile projects, analyzed high level business requirements and created detail oriented story cards
- Working on Water fall projects, scheduled multiple working sessions with business and created Functional, non-functional and Transition requirements
- Have written multiple scenarios as part of fit criteria, which formed the basis for testers test plans
- Acted as the first point of contact for developers and testers with questions regarding the expectations of the story cards and/or requirements
- · Communicated and reviewed the work products with the stakeholders as necessary
- Co-ordinated the effort between multiple analysts when there was more than one BSA assigned to the project
- Mentored and Coached the BSAs new to the company, job, and/or, new to the project and positioned them for success
- Worked closely with Project manager in Triaging the defects and managing them until resolution
- Performed high level business acceptance testing as needed
- Was involved in creating RFP, Vendor scoring and selection process for Identity and Access Management solution

Business Analyst Jan 2004 to Jul 2005

Marsh & Mclennan Companies, Inc. i1/4 Sunrise, FL

- Gathered Business and Technical Requirements by interacting with business and technical folks. This involved meeting with IT, Agents, Adjusters and Customers.
- Used Use cases and Process flow maps in generating requirements.
- Involved in Analysis and documentation of Requirements. In performing this, extensively used Microsoft tools including Word, Excel,

PowerPoint, Visio and Lotus Notes.

- Worked as a liaison between the Business groups and IT and made recommendations on requirements.
- Involved in developing test plans and test cases.
- Conducted Integration, System, Functional, GUI, Regression, Performance and User Acceptance Testing from time to time.

Call Center Representative Mar 2003 to Dec 2003

Jordan's Furniture i1/4 Melrose, MA

- Served customers by answering inquiries, resolving problems, fulfilling requests.
- Clarified desired information by researching, locating, and providing information .
- Fulfilled requests by clarifying desired information, completing transactions, and forwarding requests
- Sold additional services by recognizing opportunities to up-sell accounts, and explaining new features.
- Maintained call center database by entering information

Education and Training

MBA, Finance, Marketing 2003 Osmania University i1/4 City, State, India